原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：浏览器  斑驳的小屋
■
翻译：小蛮腰  王二川
翻译：吃不胖的毓杰  君君
校对：君君  somehacker
后期：8T     总监：somehacker
介意我调小声点吗
Do you mind if I turn this down?
不介意
No.
菲尔有事找你
You're on with Phil.
戴维斯  光年项目怎样了
Davis. Where are we with the Lightyear deal?
银行不肯让步
The banks won't budge, you know.
他们拿一些规章条例当借口
They're claiming regulations as an excuse.
和之前哈斯克尔体育用品那个项目一样
Same thing they did with Haskell Athletic.
好吧  他们还想要更多的资本缓冲吗
Yeah, yeah... What, they want more cushion?
是的  5%
Yup. 5%.
好吧  我女儿和你在一块吗
All right, very good. Is my daughter with you?
你好  爸爸
Hey, dad.
你妈生气了  你们为什么不说话了
Your mother's upset. Why aren't you talking?
那是我和妈之间的事
That's between me and mom.
给她打个电话吧  她那个倔脾气
Well, you should call. She's hard-headed.
我也遗传了
Well, I guess that's where I get it from.
周日晚饭的时候再说行吗
Well, we'll talk it out on Sunday at dinner, okay?
-好吧宝贝  回聊  -再见  爸爸
- All right love. Bye-bye. - Bye, dad.
看我们家冰箱了吗
Have you looked at the refrigerator yet?
什么  冰箱
Huh? The refrigerator?
没错  厨房里冷藏食物的铁箱子
Yeah. The box in our kitchen that keeps things cold.
不  还没  冰箱怎么了
No. Uh, what about it?
漏液  已经两个星期了
It's leaking... it's been leaking for two weeks.
冰箱漏液了
The refrigerator's leaking.
别来这招  重复一遍我的话
Please don't do that thing where you repeat part of what I said
就证明你听进去了一样
so I'll think you're paying attention.
我可没对你用什么花招
I'm not doing anything.
冰箱漏液了吗  我倒没注意
The refrigerator's leaking, I didn't notice.
你就不能修一下吗
Can't you just fix it?
你爸老早就把工具给你了
Your father gave you those tools.
我还有工具
I have tools?
没错  两年前就有了
Yes. From two christmases ago.
"不是我的椅子  关我屁事"
"Not my chair, not my problem."
你不就喜欢这么说吗
Is that what you say?
破碎人生
戴维斯
Davis...
她走了
She's gone.
那边那个贩卖机  我买的糖卡住了
The machine over there? Uh, my candy's stuck.
偶尔是会这样
It happens sometimes.
有钥匙什么的能打开它吗
Do you have a key or something we can open it up with?
贩卖机不归医院管
The machine doesn't belong to the hospital.
是贩卖机公司的财产
It's a vending company.
戴维斯  是爸爸妈妈
Davis, it's mom and dad.
我们打过你手机  但
We tried your cell phone but we...
我们找不到你人  所以
We can't get a hold of you, and then...
亲爱的
Oh, honey...
我们  我们这就来陪你  儿子
We're... we're coming, son.
您有一条留言
You have one saved message.
是我  你的语音信箱满了
Hey, it's me, your mailbox was full.
今天有份包裹会到
There's supposed to be a package delivered,
如果你先到家  记得应门
so if you beat me home, answer the doorbell, okay?
爱你  再见
Love. Bye.
亲爱的
Oh, honey...
致冠军贩卖机公司  逗号
Dear Champion vending company, comma.
我写信是想反映
This letter is in regards to
一次糟糕的购买经历  位于圣安德烈
a poor vending experience at St. Andre's...
不  等等
No, wait.
事关714号贩卖机
In regards to vending machine number 714
即圣安德烈医院加护病房区那一台的故障问题
located in the intensive care unit of Saint Andre's hospital.
我往机器里投了五枚25美分硬币
I put five quarters in the machine,
然后按下了B2按钮
and proceeded to push B2,
按理说应该掉下一袋M&M's巧克力  句号
which should've given me the peanut M&M's, period.
遗憾的是  并没有
Regrettably, it did not.
我当时很饿  那让我十分不快
I found this upsetting as I was very hungry.
而且我妻子就在那十分钟前离开了人世
And also, my wife had died 10 minutes earlier.
我并不是说这是你们的错
I'm not saying that was your fault.
我们遇到了车祸
We were in a car accident.
我却奇迹般地毫发无伤
Remarkably, I escaped without a scratch.
我并不是想给这次索赔添油加醋博同情
I'm not trying to dramatize my claim,
只是想把事情说得详细些
I just wanna be thorough.
或许我该从头开始
Maybe I should start from the beginning.
我每天早上五点半起床
I get up every morning at 5:30.
我在市场部门工作
I work in the markets
所以提早抢占先机很重要
so it's important to get an early start.
我并不是在暗示我的工作要比
Not to imply that it's any more important than, say,
面包师或者收费员要高档
a Baker or a toll collector.
那些也是体面的工作
Those are fine, respectable jobs.
我早起只是为了通勤
I just mean that I commute.
我赶7:15的车离开白原市
I catch the 7:15 out of White Plains.
似乎每天坐车的都是同一些人
It's pretty much the same crowd during the week.
约翰是扬基体育场的地勤
John works the ground crew at yankee stadium.
第一次碰面就问我做什么营生
The first time we met, he asked what I did,
我告诉他
and I told him...
我是做床垫零售的
Uh, retail mattresses.
床垫零售  太棒了
Retail mattresses? That's amazing...
我也不知道为什么骗他  突发奇想罢了
I don't know why. It just popped into my head.
那次以后我就躲着他  因为
I avoided him after that 'cause
他那口浓重的咖啡味实在太难闻了
I couldn't stand his hot coffee breath.
不好意思
Excuse me...
他应该也心知肚明
I think he knew.
我从没料到自己也会成为
I never thought I'd be one of those people
手提公文包的一员
who carried a briefcase.
那总让我联想到
It always reminds me of
拎着午餐盒去上学的时光
carrying a lunch box to school.
现在还生产那玩意儿吗
Do they still make those?
米奇尔先生
Mister Mitchell.
早上好
Morning.
茱莉亚的父亲
Julia's father
是我所在投资公司的创始人之一
is a founding partner at the investment firm I work at.
典型的任人唯亲
Nepotism in its truest form.
我27岁起  他就开始"调教"我了
He started grooming me when I was 27.
我讨厌这个词
I hate that word.
对猴子才叫调教呢
Monkeys groom.
我在这向你招手呢  看得见我吗伙计
Wavin' at you from over here. Can you see me, buddy?
公司虽小
It's a small firm,
但经手的钱可不少
but we handle quite a bit of money.
具体多少我不想说
I don't wanna say how much,
总觉得不太合适
'cause I think it would be inappropriate.
朝着赚钱的方向看就对了
Just look over where the money is.
好吧  是60亿美元
Okay, it's $6 billion.
各类新兴市场  基础设施
Emerging markets, infrastructure,
发电厂  通讯行业  海洋馆
power plants, telecom, seaworld,
车窗的雨刮
windshield wipers...
超越
只要你想得到  一切行业我们都能掺和
You name it. Doesn't matter what industry.
我们低价进  高价出
We buy 'em cheap, and we sell it for a bundle.
但都不是实物买卖
But none of it's real.
手里不用积压任何商品
Nothing to hold in my hands.
进进出出的只有数字而已
It's all just numbers.
电脑将数据
Computer codes being transferred
通过网络传输出去
electronically through the air.
一切就在我们眼前发生
Right in front of us.
法国诗人保罗·瓦勒里
The French poet, Paul Valery,
有一句话说的没错
was right when he said,
"未来已经不再是当年那回事了"
"The future isn't what it used to be."
菲尔·伊斯特伍德  我的岳父
Phil Eastwood. My father-in-law.
F-I-L  菲尔
F-I-L. Phil.
我觉得这缩写简直笑死人了
I think the acronym is hysterical.
我知道菲尔是由PH打头
I know Phil is spelled with a P-H,
但还是忍不住暗自好笑
but it still makes me laugh in my head.
戴维斯
Davis.
你好[韩语]
狗屁
Bullshit.
我和茱莉亚在一次派对中邂逅
I met Julia at a party.
谁把这张该死的椅子放那的
Who put that goddamn chair there?
不是我的椅子
Not my chair...
不是我的椅子  关我屁事  我经常这么说
Not my chair, not my problem, that's what I say.
一个共同的朋友转告我她觉得我很性感
A mutual friend said she thought I was hot.
我也夸赞了她一番
I returned the compliment.
我喜欢带贝壳和海马花纹的东西
I like things with seashells and seahorses on 'em,
比如毯子和毛巾
like blankets and towels...
大约三小时后我们就发生了关系
We had sex about three hours later.
永远在一起
Forever...
我觉得菲尔一开始似乎不是很喜欢我
I don't think Phil liked me that much at first.
我是在泽西岛长大的
I grew up in Jersey.
我不是出身于富贵人家
I didn't come from money.
在订婚派对上  我还吐在了冰雕上
And I puked on the ice sculpture at our engagement party.
他也跟我说过一次
Also, he told me once...
我不喜欢你  戴维斯
I don't like you, Davis.
茱莉亚是个好姑娘  很善良
Julia was a nice girl. A good person.
她的工作是照顾特殊儿童
She worked with special needs children,
她开心时会扑哧大笑
she snorted when she laughed
每次看到双子塔崩塌的镜头则会潸然泪下
and cried every time they showed footage of the towers falling.
除此之外
Other than that,
我并不是很了解她
I don't think I knew who she really was.
她总说我心不在焉
She always said I didn't pay attention.
可能你会觉得这些事
Perhaps you'll find this information irrelevant
跟我的退款要求并不相干
in your deliberation of my refund,
但我想你有权利知道这整个故事
but I think you deserve the whole story.
诚挚的  戴维斯 C. 米奇尔
Sincerely, Davis C. Mitchell.
你还好吗
You okay?
早上好
Morning.
早安  艾米  那是给我的吗
Morning, Amy. Is that me?
是的  没错
Yeah... that's it.
好的  把这个发出去好吗
Great. Put this in the outgoing mail?
很重要
It's important.
我...
I, um...
我没想到你今天会来上班
I didn't think you were coming in today,
他们说你没有
they said you weren't...
节哀顺变  戴维斯
I am so sorry, Davis.
谢谢你  艾米
Thank you, Amy.
等你抽出空的时候  能给我一份
When you get a minute, can I get the revenue numbers
阿尔德曼国际的收益表吗
on Alderman International?
另外把我跟鲍勃·莱斯的午餐安排推后
And can you push my lunch with Bob Rice?
我有一堆进度要跟
I got a lot of catching up to do.
好的
Yeah...
我交给你们
I handed you people
十亿美元的投资资本
a billion dollars' worth of committed capital
你们跟我说只找到总市值1.5亿的
and all you can give me is 150 million dollars'
公司去收购
worth of companies to buy.
就没人喜欢购物吗  难道要请我妈来教你们吗
Doesn't anyone like to shop? Should I call my mother?
菲尔
Phil.
他们打电话去我家了  跟我说你来上班了
They called the house. Told me you were up here.
是吗  好吧
They did? Okay.
我早上和克莱顿·布朗谈了一下
I talked to Clayton Brown this morning.
我想我已经劝服他冷静下来了
And I think I talked him off the ledge on that thing.
去喝一杯怎么样
Look, why don't we go grab a drink?
我快忙死了 菲尔
I'm buried, Phil.
两周没跟光年项目
Two weeks out from lightyear,
我得拼命往前赶
and I gotta get some momentum going.
戴维斯  去喝一杯吧
Davis, let's grab a drink.
跟你说  这里的鸡尾酒卖18块一杯
You know, the cocktails run about 18 bucks a pop here.
我真搞不懂
I don't get it.
我们一直没怎么聊过  戴维斯
We haven't really talked, Davis.
从一开始就这样
Not since... everything.
我爱茱莉亚
I loved Julia.
非常爱她
So much.
父亲的爱
It's a father's love.
男人失去了妻子  叫鳏夫
A man loses his wife, he's a widower.
孩子失去双亲  就是孤儿
A child loses a parent, they're an orphan.
但没有一个词语  是形容失去了孩子的人
But losing a child...there's no word for this.
也不该有
And there shouldn't be.
而你
But you...
你和我还要继续生活
You and I have to continue on.
我想告诉你  你一直对我很重要
I want you to know you've been a value to me,
不只是生意上  是对我的人生而言
and not just in business, but in my life.
并且...
And, uh...
你将情绪隐藏起来
You keep your emotions close to the vest,
那样很好  很坚强
that's good, that's strong.
我也是
I do the same.
主要是氛围
It's the atmosphere.
什么
What?
所以酒水价格才会这么贵
That's why the drinks are so expensive.
你其实是在为这里的氛围买单
You're paying for the atmosphere.
我刚突然想到的
It just occurred to me.
戴维斯  听我说
Davis, listen,
还有其他的事需要费心
there's some other business that needs looking after.
是她的保单
It's the insurance policy.
我想用茱莉亚的保险金
I'd like to take her money
以她的名义成立一个基金会
and start a foundation in Julia's name.
基金会
Foundation...
优秀奖学金
A merit-based scholarship
每年都会颁发给
awarded annually
一名最受之无愧的学生
to one student who's most deserving.
多少钱
How much are we talking about?
大概260万
About 2.6.
斯蒂文会着手做这件事
Steven's gonna get the ball rolling.
那将成为她遗留给这世界的东西
This'll be her legacy.
遗留
Legacy...
尊敬的冠军自动收货公司
Dear champion vending company.
我是戴维斯·米奇尔
This is Davis Mitchell.
又是我
Again.
我的索赔事宜
There have been some recent developments
最近有了新进展
in my claim for reimbursement,
我想尽量表达清楚我的意思
And I'd like to represent myself as accurately as possible.
晚饭好了  儿子
Dinner's ready, son.
首先  有个很奇怪的包裹
First, there was a strange package
挡在我的车库前
blocking my garage.
妈
Mom?
我猜是个咖啡机
I think it's a cappuccino machine.
我没买咖啡机
I didn't order a cappuccino machine.
是茱莉亚买的
It was in Julia's name.
其次  我父亲早上7点钟
Then, my dad was fertilizing the lawn
就开始给草坪施肥
at 7:00 in the morning.
爸  你在干什么
Dad! What are you doing?
是施肥的季节啊  戴维斯
It's the season, Davis.
你该施肥了  必须趁现在
You should do this. You need to.
好让土壤肥沃一些
Get the soil ready.
我请了专人负责这事的
I have someone for that.
那他们知道舞毒蛾吗
Do they know about gypsy moths?
什么
What?
舞毒蛾  它们会让树死去
Gypsy moths. They'll destroy your trees.
一开始是虫蛹
It starts as a caterpillar.
它们会吃掉树叶  产卵
They eat the leaves, lay eggs...
小区里发现了这种虫子吗
And they're coming here, to this neighborhood?
虽然还不确定
Well, they don't know for sure,
但你还是告诉负责除虫的人撒点药
but you should tell your guy to spray.
当然还有  火车上的陌生人
And of course, the train incident...
我觉得我应该告诉你些事
I feel like I should tell you something.
我是做金融的
Um, I'm in finance.
我也不知道我之前为何告诉你
I don't know why I told you
我是做床垫生意的
that I worked in the mattress business.
大概是我当时没想到
I guess I didn't expect to see you
连续5年每天都能见到你
every day for five years.
你觉得我是个混蛋吧
You think I'm a dick.
我已经不给洋基队干了
I don't work for the Yankees anymore.
候补队员区排水出问题了  我被开除了
Got fired over a drainage issue in the visitors' bullpen.
我现在在市中心一家鞋店做保安
I work security now at parade of shoes in midtown.
该死的工作  抱歉
Fuckin' job. Excuse me.
我的混蛋老板比我小30岁
My little prick of a boss. He's 30 years younger than me.
我恨不得进去
I just wanna go in there
照着他的脸当面给几拳
and smash his little prick face.
天啊
Jeez.
我不爱我老婆
I didn't love my wife.
我懂的  说出来很可悲
I know, it's sad... It's sad to say,
但是现在她不在了
but now that she's gone,
我却没有任何悲伤或痛苦的感觉
I don't even feel sad or pain or hurt, or...
那你是什么感觉
Well, what do you feel?
我不知道我为什么那么做
I couldn't tell you why I did it.
所以你就拉了那个把手
So that's when you pulled it.
也许是因为我终于诚实了
Maybe because I was finally being honest.
是的
Yes.
你知道拉那个把手火车会紧急停车吧
And you knew that would stop the train, correct?
我本来不太确定  但我希望是这样
Well, I wasn't positive, but I was hoping.
我只能说
All I can say is,
感觉当时就是紧急状况
it felt like a legitimate emergency.
他刚丧妻
His wife just died.
戴维斯  也许你应该
Davis, maybe you should
来跟我们住一段时间
come stay with us for a while.
看开些
Take it easy.
我们有空房间
We have the extra room.
你还可以帮我把凉亭搭起来
I could sure use help putting that gazebo together.
怎么样
How's that sound?
茱莉亚&戴维斯·米奇尔
希尔斯顿大道17号
别忘了让人喷杀虫剂
Remember to tell your guy to spray.
你好  又是我  戴维斯·米奇尔
Hello again, it's Davis Mitchell.
我父母今天下午回坦帕了
My parents left for tampa this afternoon,
他们走后我在机场待了2小时
and I stayed at the airport an extra two hours
看人们拖着行李  步履匆匆
watching people walk back and forth with their luggage in tow.
我觉得突然自己充满了...等等
I find I'm suddenly filled with... wait...
是被...好奇感淹没了
Overwhelmed by... A growing sense of curiosity...
那些包里都有什么
What are in these bags?
我想知道如果他们
I wanna know what these people
要在水牛城待4天  有哪些东西是必不可少的
can't do without for four days in Buffalo.
我想打开看看每个箱子
I wanna go through every one of them
把他们的东西堆成一堆
and dump their shit in a huge pile.
至于那个国民警卫队员  我想握住他的枪
And the national guard guy? I wanna hold his gun.
我想保家卫国
I wanna protect my country.
我开始注意之前从没看到过的东西
I'm starting to notice things I never saw before.
也许我看到过
Maybe I saw them.
我只是没细心留意而已
I just wasn't paying attention.
因为某种原因
For some reason,
所有的一切都像是隐喻
everything has become a metaphor.
隐喻
Metaphor...
我像是一棵被连根拔起的树  不  等下
I am the uprooted tree. No, wait...
我是将树连根拔起的风暴
I am the storm that uprooted the tree.
我是和低气压系统正面相撞的冷锋
I am the cold front that collided with the low-pressure system.
写太过了
Too much.
早  艾米  贴张邮票
Morning, Amy. Put a stamp on that?
尊敬的自动售货机公司  还有件事
There's something else, dearest vending company.
一直在搅弄着我的大脑  使之无法宁静
It's been scratching at the inside of my head.
我一秒钟都忍不了了
I couldn't take it one second longer.
该死的冰箱竟然在漏水
The goddamn refrigerator was leaking.
我可不敢说自己是能工巧匠
Now, I wouldn't say I'm handy by any means.
机械白痴更贴近现实
Mechanically retarded would be closer to the truth.
但菲尔也亲口说过
But Phil said it himself,
"如果你想把东西修好
"If you wanna fix something..."
得先拆掉所有零部件
You have to take everything apart...
找到重要的点"
"...and figure out what's important."
找到能让你变得更坚强的东西
What'll make you stronger.
修复人心
Repairing the human heart
就像修车
is like repairing an automobile.
检视所有的部分
Just examine everything.
然后就能重新组装好
Then you can put it all back together.
重新组装好
Put it all back together...
喂
Hello?
你好  请问是戴维斯·米奇尔先生吗
Hello. Mr. Davis Mitchell?
什么事
Yes?
我是凯伦·莫里诺
This is Karen Moreno
冠军自动售货公司的工作人员
from champion vending company.
我是客户服务部的
I'm with customer service.
我打电话
I'm calling in regards
是因为收到了您的投诉信  米奇尔先生
to your complaint letters, mister Mitchell.
目前为止一共收到了4封
There's been four so far.
你是客户服务部的吗
You're with the customer service department?
是的  先生  客户服务部
Yes, sir. I am the customer service department.
只有我一个人
It's just me.
你们经常在凌晨两点钟给顾客打电话吗
Do you usually make service calls at 2:00 in the morning?
不  不是  从来没有
No. Not really. Never.
我...我很抱歉打扰您休息
I... I apologize for the inconvenience.
我只是想发泄一下
I was just venting.
我从没想过真的会有人读  很抱歉如果...
I didn't expect anybody to read them. Sorry if...
你的信把我看哭了  米奇尔先生
Your letters made me cry, mister Mitchell.
你找到可以倾诉的人了吗
Do you have anyone to talk to?
我  我会把你的投诉提交到管理部门
I... I'm gonna submit your claim to management.
与此同时  有什么其他事
In the meantime is there something else
是我能为你做的吗  米奇尔先生
I can do for you, mister Mitchell?
等等  等一下
Wait, wait.
凯伦·莫里诺  你是叫这名字吗
Karen Moreno, that's your name?
这样很怪  我  我不该打给你的
This is weird. I... I shouldn't have called.
我  我会在合适的时间联系您
I... I'm going to contact you at a more reasonable hour.
再次抱歉  米奇尔先生
I'm sorry again, mister Mitchell.
我这样太不专业了
This is so unprofessional.
客户服务也是专门的职业吗
Customer service is a profession?
有的人沉浸在悲痛中不能自拔
Some people wallow through their grief.
我妻子会做饭
My wife, she cooks.
太好吃了  玛格特  这是什么
This is delicious, Margot, what is it?
茱莉亚有没有跟你说过我们为什么吵架
Did Julia tell you what we were fighting about?
我给她买了浴巾  她不喜欢
I bought her these bath towels and she didn't like 'em,
所以她没告诉我就退了
so she took 'em back without telling me.
我们3天没说话
And we hadn't spoken for three days.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
失陪下
Excuse me.
你好  凯伦
Hi, Karen.
你怎么知道是我
How did you know it was me?
我已经把你存进手机通讯录了
I have you programmed into my phone.
我明白了  我也不知道自己是什么感觉
Oh, I see. I'm not sure how I feel about that.
关于你的投诉
There's something else I wanted to bring
我想告知你一下
to your attention regarding your claim.
好的
Okay.
在我们之前的交谈中
During our previous conversation,
你说我的工作就不是专门的职业
you implied that my job wasn't a profession.
抱歉  我并没有侮辱的意思
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it as an insult.
我知道  可这又让我思考
I know. But it made me think,
我觉得也许你说得对
and I concluded that you might be right.
上帝保佑爱迪生联合电气公司
God bless Con Ed.
所以就有了光
And there was light!
是啊  我要走了  谢谢你的晚餐
Yeah. I've gotta go. Thank you for dinner.
不是吧
Really?
"莫里诺"在西语中是棕色的意思  你知道吗
"Moreno" Means brown in Spanish, did you know that?
是的  我当然知道
Yes, I did, of course.
你是棕发吗
Do you have brown hair?
不是  是金发
No, it's blonde.
你是西班牙后裔吗
Are you of Spanish descent?
不是  你问这个干什么
No. Why do you ask?
我只是试图想象你的样子
I'm just trying to paint a mental picture.
不好意思  请问凯伦·莫里诺在吗
Excuse me, is Karen Moreno here?
谁
Who?
金发  灰褐色眼睛
Blonde hair, hazel eyes,
但她并不是西班牙裔  不像她的名字
but not Hispanic like her name suggests?
嗨  你在哪
Hi, where are you?
我去了那家餐厅
I was there, in the diner.
我在卡座坐了一会
I sat in a booth for a few minutes.
我还在那个
I even played a song
小点唱机上点了首歌  然后
on the little baby jukebox, and then...
我也不知道  我觉得很难过就走了
I dunno, I got sad, so I left.
你点了什么歌
What song did you play?
红心乐团的《为你疯狂》
Crazy On You, by Heart.
那首歌让你觉得难过吗
That made you sad?
不是那首歌
Not so much the song.
你的煎饼好吃吗
How are your pancakes?
我  我在停车场
Oh, I... I'm in the parking lot.
什么
What?
你抽烟啊
You're a smoker.
是大麻  药用大麻  我有处方
It's cannabis. I have a prescription.
好吧
Okay.
你比我想象的要年轻
You look younger than I expected.
你可以进来吗
Do you think you could come inside?
这个嘛  问题是...
Oh, well, it's just that...
我在这看你坐在窗边
I have this nice image of you
吃煎饼  这个画面很美好
sitting there in the window eating pancakes.
也许就该这样  知道吗
Maybe that's all it's supposed to be, ya know?
好吧  但我能看到的你
Yeah, but my image of you is
只是一个坐在卡罗拉车里抽大麻的影子
a shadowy figure smoking pot in a Corolla.
算了  我该走了  没错  我要走了
You know what? I should go. Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna go.
不  不  不  等等
No, no, no, wait.
我还有一封信要给你
I have another letter here for you.
寄给我吧
Put it in the mail.
我觉得这个可行  菲尔
I think it's for real, Phil.
如果他们第二季度的盈余
If their second quarter earnings
有增长的迹象
are an indication of growth,
哪怕只是两三个百分点
even just two or three percent,
这个险也值得冒
then it's a risk worth taking.
戴维斯  你需要纸吗
Davis, do you need some paper?
对于我们的讨论  你有什么要说的吗
Is there something you'd like to contribute to the discussion?
的确有  不过我是要提个问题
Yes, actually. But it's more of a question.
你们有人觉得《为你疯狂》是首悲伤的歌吗
Would any of you consider Crazy On You to be a sad song?
前提是你们熟悉
And that's from, you know, assuming
红心乐团的曲目
that you're familiar with the Heart catalog.
电梯下行
Going down.
办公室
凯伦的收件箱
有什么可以帮到您的吗
Can I help you?
是的  我要找凯伦
Oh, yeah. I'm looking for Karen.
不好意思  你是哪位
I'm sorry, who are you?
我是戴维斯  我有事情
I'm Davis. I have a...
要找客服部
customer service issue.
我叫卡尔  这是我的公司
Oh, I'm Carl. This is my company.
有什么问题
What's the problem?
我真的不能跟你详谈  卡尔
I really can't get into it, Carl.
要说的东西太多了
There's way too much ground to cover.
不过谢谢你的关心
But thanks for your concern.
你收到基金会的提案了吗
Did you get the foundation proposal?
我需要你签字确认  才能进行下一步
I'm gonna need you to sign off before we move forward.
听着  你有没有想过要找人聊聊
Listen, have you thought about talking to someone?
我是指专业人士
Professionally, I mean.
我没头朝下
I didn't go upside down!
你父亲觉得我疯了
Your father thinks I'm losing my mind.
喂
Hello?
我刚拆了一个价值两千美金的卡布奇诺咖啡机
I just dismantled a $2,000 Cappuccino machine.
你为什么打给我  米奇尔先生
Why did you call me, Mister Mitchell?
你为什么要接
Why'd you answer?
是因为你的信
There's something about your letters.
我正坐在浴缸里重读其中的一封信
I'm re-reading one right now in my tub.
我不是在泡澡  我只是坐在这
I'm not bathing or anything. I just sit here.
这里很安静  而且我也不想吵醒我儿子
It's quiet, and I don't wanna wake up my son.
我提过我有个儿子吗
Did I mention I have a son?
没有
No.
好吧  他15岁
Yeah, he's 15.
但看起来像12岁  处事风格又像21岁
But looks 12 and acts 21.
他聪明得很  但他把我吓得不轻
So bright, but he scares the shit outta me.
凯伦
Karen...
我  我得挂了
I... I have to go.
你不该去我办公室来找我的  米奇尔先生
You shouldn't have come to my office, Mister Mitchell.
这开了一个很危险的先例
This sets a dangerous precedent.
危险
Dangerous?
亲爱的凯伦  既然我们差点就见面了
Dear Karen, is it okay that I address you directly
我是不是可以直接写信给你了
now that we've almost met?
我觉得可以
I'll assume so.
我今天在火车上
I was on the train today,
看到有一个女人盯着我看
and I saw a woman staring at me.
她似乎有一种独特之处
There was something about her.
于是我就过去打了招呼
So I went and introduced myself.
我叫戴维斯
I'm Davis.
我们认识吗
Do we know each other?
不认识
No.
我  我不是想要钓你之类的
I'm... I'm not trying to pick you up or anything.
我只是  你看上去很面熟
I just... You look familiar.
可不可以  抱歉  我...
Is it okay... Sorry, I...
今天过得不顺吗
Tough day?
不  没有  不是
No. Not really, no.
我的工作其实并不难
My job isn't really that difficult.
脏活累活大多是我手底下的人干了
It's the guys underneath me who do most of the heavy lifting.
我只是坐享其成而已
I just take all the credit for it.
大多数人都不会承认这种事
Most people wouldn't admit that.
我大学的最后一年是作弊通过的
I actually cheated my way through my last year of college.
我让一个叫埃德蒙的人替我写所有的论文
I had this guy Edmond write all my papers for me,
有时候我会给他些摇头丸
and sometimes, I'd give him ecstasy.
其实...
You know...
她很安静  但不知道怎的
She was quiet, but for some reason,
我就想向她倾诉
I wanted to tell her things.
我发现我一边说一边在记她的脸
I found myself mapping her face as I talked.
她不知怎么就让我说起了我的妻子
Somehow, she got me talking about my wife.
我真的对她敞开了心扉
I really let her in.
然后她突然问我
Then, out of nowhere, she asked...
那你为什么娶她
So why'd you marry her?
我不知道  因为很容易
I dunno. 'Cause it was easy.
下一站  斯卡斯代尔
Next stop, Scarsdale.
我本想问她的名字
I wanted to ask her name...
我到了
This is me.
但她转眼就消失了
But she disappeared so quick.
我接下来的十分钟一直在踹我自己
I spent the next 10 minutes kicking myself.
"我再见到这个女人的机会能有多大呢"
"What are the chances i'd ever see this woman again?"
"幸运的是  她把杂志落在座位上了"
"Fortunately, she left her magazine on the seat."
我想你知道那本杂志是寄给谁的
I think you know who it was addressed to.
斯卡斯代尔也不是她要下的站
And Scarsdale ain't her stop.
不要再玩游戏了  凯伦  我们很快就会见面的
No more games, Karen. I'll see you soon.
你  你怎么会在这里
You. What are you doing here?
-我是来找凯伦·莫里诺的  -你怎么在这里
- I'm here to see Karen Moreno. - What are you doing here?
我怎么在这里
What am I doing here?
你...你他妈到底想干什么
Who the... What the fuck do you want?
你用不着骂脏话  卡尔
You don't have to swear, Carl.
我告诉过你  我有事找客服
I told you I have a customer service issue.
搞什么
What...
卡尔  这位是戴维斯·米奇尔
Carl, this is Davis Mitchell.
我本该打电话给你的
I was supposed to call you.
你好  凯伦
Hi, Karen.
他  他投诉我们的一台机器
He, uh... he's having problems with one of the machines.
什么机器
What machine?
在圣安德烈医院加护病房的714号售卖机
Uh, Number 714, in the intensive care unit at Saint Andre's.
二楼
Second floor.
你是医生吗
You a doctor?
不  我是金融界的
No. I work in finance.
-那这是...  -卡尔  亲爱的
- Well, what... - Carl. Honey.
让我来处理  没事的
I'll handle this. It's okay.
现在是半夜11点  凯伦
It's 11:00, Karen.
你他妈的为什么跑到我们家来
Why the hell are you at our house?
这是我家  好吗
It's my house, okay?
你要么进去  要么回家  我能处理这事的
Now go inside, or go home. I'll handle this.
没事的  走吧
It's okay. Come on.
我刚好来到这附近
I was in the neighborhood.
你不该来这的
You shouldn't be here.
你知道吗  我  我有男朋友
You know what? I... I'm with someone.
卡尔  我们在一起
Carl. We're together.
我不该给你打电话的
I shouldn't have called you.
我也不该跟踪你
And I shouldn't have started following you.
那很不专业
It's very unprofessional.
你怎么了  你的衣服
What happened to you? Your clothes...
我十分钟前在车里写了这封信
I wrote this in the car 10 minutes ago.
这是最后一封了
It's the last one.
亲爱的凯伦  菲尔去死吧
Dear Karen. Fuck Phil.
你想告诉我这到底是怎么回事吗
You wanna tell me what's going on?
没什么  我本该打电话给他的
Nothing. I was supposed to call him.
我们把事情解决了
We sorted it out.
你跟这家伙有一腿吗
Are you having an affair with this guy?
没有  我想他只是孤独罢了
No, I'm not. He's lonely, I think.
我也说不清  他有点不对劲
I don't know, he's just a little... off.
你几点的飞机
What time's your flight?
那是个很美的城市  凯伦
It's a good-looking city, Karen.
你也可以去上技校  就像我们
And you could go to tech school, like we...
像我们谈过的那样
like we talked about.
我可以  我再开一家仓库
I can... I'll open up a new warehouse.
像现在的两倍那么大
Twice, two times the square footage...
而克里斯
And Chris, I mean...
他在这很煎熬  你知道吗
He's struggling here, you know?
新的开始也许是件好事
A new start could be good.
亲爱的凯伦  菲尔去死吧
Dear Karen. Fuck Phil.
他把我叫到他办公室
He called me into his office...
我暂停了光年项目
I pulled the plug on Lightyear.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
直觉
Gut feeling.
老实说  你最近的判断力不太可靠
To be honest, your judgment of late has been questionable.
为什么这么说  菲尔
How so, Phil?
你是不是把我们洗手间里的电灯组件给拆了
Did you take apart the lighting fixture in our bathroom?
是的  没错
Yes. I did.
还有你的电脑
And your computer?
我猜洗手间的隔间也是你拆的吧
I assume you're responsible for the washroom stall.
是我干的  没错
That was my work, yes.
为什么
Why?
这问题有点难答
Well, that's a little harder to answer.
你说说看
Try me.
比如说  洗手间的小隔间
The bathroom stall, for example?
门吱嘎吱嘎作响
The door was squeaking.
而且很可能响了很长一段时间了
And it had probably been that way for quite some time.
我却从未注意到
I just never noticed.
而现在  我发现了
And now, I'm noticing
各种各样的事情  菲尔
all different kinds of things, Phil,
我想知道它们的本质和原理
and I wanna see how they work.
就像那个钟
Like that clock.
纯手工  艺术杰作
Pure craftsmanship. Artistry!
那是我曾祖母的  19世纪90年代的东西
That belonged to my great-grandmother. 1890s.
我想拆了它
I wanna rip it apart and
把零部件一个个摆放在地板上
spread it out all over the floor.
我无意冒犯你的曾祖母
And no offense to your great-grandmother,
只是我看到那种款式的钟
but I see a clock like that,
就像知道内部结构是怎样的
and I wanna know what it looks like inside.
戴维斯
Davis.
你停职一段时间吧
I want you to take some time off.
他妈的
Fuck him,
他靠在桌边上的姿势
and the way he leans on the corner of his desk
袖子卷起
with his sleeves rolled up
像是准备动手挖出一条沟
like he's about to dig a ditch.
以后没有想象的办公室鸿沟了  凯伦
No more imaginary office ditches, Karen.
从现在开始  只剩我和我的工具
From now on, it's me and my tools.
我本来打算开车回家的
I intended to drive home
但突然就转道走了中城隧道
but accidentally turned for the midtown tunnel.
红宝石路
Ruby drive...
也许并不是巧合
Maybe there are no accidents.
总之  似乎这个时候刚好适合找你
Anyway, it seemed like a good time to come and look for you.
左转进入水晶大道
Turn left on Crystal Avenue.
当我发现我进入了一个街区
I knew I was getting close
所有道路都以名贵的宝石命名
when I found myself in a neighborhood
我就知道快到了
where all the streets were named after precious stones.
这时我看到了
And that's when I saw it.
你是卖保险的吗
You the insurance guy?
不  我不是
Oh, no. Not me.
我以为...  我看到这制服
I thought... you know, I just saw the suit,
所以就以为...
so I figured, you know...
我只是开车路过
I was just driving by,
看到你们在干活  挺有意思的
and I, uh, saw you guys working. Looks like fun.
好吧 有意思
Yeah, fun.
你们到底在这做什么
What exactly are you doing here?
我们得先把这整栋房子拆了
Well, we gotta tear the whole thing down
然后他们才好重建
before they rebuild.
需要我帮忙吗
Can I, uh, help you out?
什么...
What...
你只要告诉我
I mean, you just, you know, you just tell me
要我做什么就行  不用付我钱
what to do, you don't have to pay me.
拜托  哥们  别搞我  好吗
Come on, pal, don't bust my balls, all right?
你是保险公司的  对吗
You're the insurance guy, right?
巴里派你来搞我吗
Barry sent you over here to bust my balls?
不  我不认识巴里
No, I don't know who Barry is.
不  我...  我...
No, I... you know, I...
其实  我甚至可以付钱给你
Actually, you know, I'll pay you, huh?
不如  我给你50块
How 'bout, uh, 50... I'll give you 50 bucks.
你这到底是想搞什么鬼  兄弟
What kinda shit you trying to pull here, pal?
不不  我不是警察  我只想帮忙
No, no, no, I'm not a cop. I... I just wanna help.
我...  我给你...
You know what, I'll... You know, I'll give you, uh...
我给你241块
I'll give you $241.
拿啊  拿着吧  我会努力干活的
Go on, take it. I'll work hard.
不不不  别用那个  别用那个
No, no. No, don't use that, don't use that.
给  戴上这个  用着个...
Here. Put these on, use this...
现在去砸墙吧
Now knock the wall down.
他简直是个怪物
This guy's a fuckin' animal.
他可能是个瘾君子
He's probably a crackhead.
瘾君子才不会给别人两百块
Crackheads don't give people $200.
给20块他们都肯给你舔鸡巴
They suck dick for $20.
你应该知道
I mean, you should know.
好吧  别问  挺尴尬的
Yeah, don't ask, it's embarrassing.
我关车门的时候夹到外套了
I, uh, closed the car door on my jacket,
然后你的洒水器打开了
and your sprinklers turned on.
然后  车子的那个破锁...
Then, the stupid lock...
有时候会卡住  我打不开...
It sometimes gets stuck... I couldn't...
你抽高了  是吗
You're high, aren't you?
只是一点...
A little bit...
你想吃点烤奶酪吗
D'you want some grilled cheese?
我需要几件工装裤
I needed some work overalls.
大概在军需店的时候我有点忘乎所以了
I guess I got a little carried away at the army surplus.
你家里...
Your whole house is just
非常温馨
lovely.
除了家电之外
Aside from the appliances,
人人都渴望住进这样的房子里
it's the kind of house people dream of living in.
我讨厌这间房子
I hate this house.
华而不实
It's just shiny stuff.
我不能和你上床  那很危险
I can't have sex with you. It'd be dangerous.
又说这个话
There's that word again.
卡尔是真的出城了吗
Is Carl really out of town,
还是你把他剁碎了
or did you just chop him up into little pieces
装进袜子抽屉里
and stuff him in your sock drawer?
真搞笑  我连装袜子的抽屉都没有
That's ridiculous. I don't have a sock drawer.
那你的袜子放哪里
Where do you keep all your socks?
和我的内裤塞在一起
In the same drawer as my underwear.
什么
What?
我只是...  我只是觉得
I just... You know, I just think
女士的内衣裤应该要有个地方单独放
a woman's underwear is deserving of its own space.
我能做的只有这些了
This is all I can handle.
可以了
That's fine.
我们一起睡吧
Let's just fall asleep together.
一起吗
Together?
分床  一起睡着
Together apart.
其实我并不爱卡尔
I'm not in love with Carl, you know.
他是个好男人  真的
He's a good man. He really is.
他爱我  甚至爱得有点过火
He loves me. Probably more than he should.
但我不知道...
But I dunno...
我想做到你所做的事
I'd like to be able to do what you do.
完全坦诚
To be completely honest.
你刚刚就做到了啊
I think you just were.
差得远呢
Not even close.
你一定是克里斯了
You must be Chris.
你干我妈了吗
You fuckin' my mom?
没有  我们只是睡在一起
No, I'm not. We were just sleeping...
妈的  她是个疯婆子
She's fuckin' crazy.
如果你没注意到  她他妈的还是个瘾君子
If you haven't noticed, she's a fuckin' pot-head.
她管这个叫大麻  因为这让她觉得
She calls it cannabis 'cause it makes her
自己不那么像他妈的瘾君子
feel like less of a fuckin' pot-head.
你很喜欢说"妈的"啊
You say "Fuck" a lot.
所以呢
So?
所以你并没有正确地使用这个词
So you're just not using it properly.
该死的  你这话什么意思
The fuck does that mean?
我就是这个意思
That's what I mean.
"妈的"是个伟大的词
"Fuck" is a great word,
但如果你说得太多  就变得廉价了
but if you use it too much, then it just loses its value.
而且这显得你很蠢
And you sound stupid.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
就像这样
Exactly.
我没觉得怎样  又显得你很蠢
I feel nothing, and you sound like an idiot.
祝你今天开心
Have a good one!
你他妈...
Who the F...
嗨  我是戴维斯·米奇尔
Hi. You've reached Davis Mitchell.
我现在不方便接电话  请留言
I'm unavailable at the moment, so please leave a message.
如果你是想找茱莉亚
If you're looking for Julia,
很遗憾地通知你  她已经不在人世了
I regret to inform you that she isn't with us anymore,
所以也联系不到她
which makes her also unavailable.
戴维斯  你做得太过火了
Davis, you've taken things too far.
我非常担心你的身体健康
I am deeply concerned with your well-being.
我试着联系你
I'm trying to reach out to you,
我是想帮你  但是你拒绝了
I'm trying to help, but you refuse!
如果你不想参加
If you don't wish to participate
构建你妻子对这个世界的遗赠
in the architecture of your wife's legacy,
那就算了吧
then so be it.
联系我
Just contact me
我能帮你除掉这些负担
so I can free you from this burden.
还有一件事
One more thing.
如果你对我女儿有那么一点点的尊重
If you have any respect for the memory of my daughter,
请你删掉这该死的语音自动答复
you'll erase that fucking message.
我是客服中心的凯伦
This is Karen, customer service.
你好  客服中心的凯伦
Hello, Karen, customer service.
您好  米奇尔先生  有什么能为您效劳吗
Hello, mister Mitchell, what can I do for you today?
这听起来可能有点疯狂
This might sound crazy,
但是有辆旅行车一直在跟踪我
but there's a station wagon that's been stalking me
跟了好几天了
for the past couple of days,
那让我产生了不少的担心
and this does raise a number of concerns,
包括  A  为什么会有人跟踪我
including "A," why would anyone be following me?
B  我是不是有什么危险
"B," Am I possibly in some kind of danger?
以及  C
And "C,"
这年头谁他妈还开旅行车啊
who the fuck still drives a station wagon?
你的处方就是这里开出来的吗
This is where you get your prescription filled?
好吧  我说谎了  那不是处方
Okay, I lied. It's not a prescription.
你好  雷  这是我的朋友戴维斯
Hey, Ray. This is my friend Davis.
你好  年轻人
Hello, young man.
我最喜欢的那种  谢谢你
Ah, my favorite kind. Thank you.
这是给你的
And this is for you.
我的花园里自己长出来的  别问我怎么长的
It grows wild in my garden. Don't ask me how.
我从不碰这些东西  会让我想太多
I never touch the stuff. Makes me think too much.
你呢  要来点吗
How 'bout you? You need some?
不用
Oh, no.
那件杰作是1961年运过来的
Oh, that beauty arrived in 1961.
从巴黎弄来的
From Paris.
你们真该见识它当年的风采  真正的杰作
You should've seen 'er. A real masterpiece.
瞧瞧啊
Look at that, huh?
很美  不是吗
Ain't that a beauty?
但现在没人喜欢旋转木马了
But nobody wants carousels anymore.
他们喜欢过山车
They want roller coasters
冲上冲下搅得人想吐的东西
that go upside down and make you puke.
你敢相信吗  我们只能拆了它
Would you believe we've got to tear it down?
真的吗
Really?
是的  要修复的地方太多了  花费太大
Yeah. Too many repairs. Too much money.
要我帮忙吗  我自己有工具
Can I help you? I have my own tools.
你真奇怪...
You're very strange...
可以的  你可以的
You got it! You got it!
凯伦·莫里诺  女士们先生们
Karen Moreno, ladies and gentlemen!
茱莉亚生前很喜欢大海
Julia loved the ocean.
以前我们的夏天
We used to spend our summers
都是在她东汉普顿区的爸妈家度过的
at her folks' place in East Hampton.
她就想待在那里
That's where she wanted to be.
你想念她吗
You miss her?
你哪个地方觉得发麻
So. Where exactly are you feeling numb?
就在这  差不多这里整个地方
Sort of in this whole area right in here.
你这样多久了
And how long have you been feeling like this?
不好说
Can't say...
十年或者十二年
Ten or twelve years.
戴维斯  不知道应该怎么告诉你
Davis... not sure how to tell you this.
来  你自己看
Come on. See for yourself.
你的心脏少了一部分
Part of your heart is missing.
什么  怎么会这样
What? How did that happen?
通过咬痕来判断
Judging by the bite pattern,
我估计是北美舞毒蛾造成的
I'd say Gypsy moths.
我操
Fuck me.
什么
Excuse me?
亲爱的凯伦  我不断地回想我的童年
Dear Karen, I keep thinking about my childhood.
当我生病的时候
When I was sick,
我会把头埋进我妈妈的膝盖里
and I would lay my head in my mother's lap,
她会不停抚摸我的头发
she'd run her fingers through my hair.
她会吻我的双眸
She'd kiss my eyelids.
那样我就会好受很多
And that made everything better.
你不觉得现在为时已晚了吗
Do you think it's too late for that?
你现在住这儿还是怎么的
Live here now or something?
不啊  你难道不该上学去吗
No. Shouldn't you be in school?
我被停学了
I'm suspended.
为什么
For what?
因为说出了事实真相
Telling the truth.
我们要做个关于世界大事的演讲
Had to do this presentation in world affairs.
有关我国军队在中东的派驻问题
About our military presence in the Middle East.
是吗  你都知道些什么
Yeah? What do you know about it?
6月5日
June 5th.
在赫尔曼德省的一次例行巡查中
During a routine patrol through the Helmand province,
丹·杜瓦克中尉的悍马车
lieutenant Dan Doviak's Hummer
停靠在了路边
pulled over to the side of the road
为了帮助一个小女孩
to assist a little girl.
出乎他们意料的是  这个小女孩
To their surprise, she had 60 pounds
身上绑着60磅的炸药
of explosives strapped to her body.
天啊
Oh, shit.
那辆悍马车瞬间被火焰吞噬
The Hummer was engulfed in flames.
阿富汗民众还在高呼
And the Afghan citizens chanted,
"歼灭美利坚"
"Death to America."
杜瓦克和他的小队被活活烧死了
Doviak and his unit were burned alive.
他们就为此把你停学了吗
They suspend you for that?
我听见开饭的铃声了
I heard the dinner bell.
今天过得好吗
Did you have a good day?
享受你的假期吗
Enjoy your little vacay?
我要把音乐换掉  宝贝
I'm changing the music, baby.
拜托  打起精神来
Come on, lighten up.
跟我说说今天发生的事情
Tell me what you did today.
你和那个可爱的姑娘约会了吗
Did you hang out with that cute girl?
就是穿着高腰牛仔裤的那个
The one with the high-waisted jeans?
那种打扮  可不是每个人都会这么出彩
You know, not everyone can pull that look off.
对吧
Right?
你是当真的吗
Are you for real right now?
我和你们的校长塔希安小姐谈过了
I spoke with your principal, Miss... Tersian?
我觉得她这人十分体贴  真心待人
I found her to be very thoughtful and empathetic.
好消息是  她允许你周一复课
The good news is, she's letting you come back starting Monday.
你得去心理辅导老师那里  要去数周
You have to spend a few weeks with the counselor,
不过我觉得他们已经算是轻易放过你了
but I think you're getting off pretty easy.
那坏消息是什么
What's the bad news?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
一个陌生男人正在我们家吃饭
There's some random guy eating in our house
恰好趁你的男友兼上司出城时
while your boyfriend/boss is out of town,
并且你还在我面前跟我吹
and you're bragging to me
你跟我那个拉拉校长进行了一次交心的长谈
about a heart-to-heart you had with my dyke principal?
你...饶了我吧  好吗
Would you just... Okay? Gimme a break!
戴维斯是我的朋友
Davis is a friend of mine.
我们最近一起消磨时间
We've been spending time together
因为朋友间本就该如此
because that's what friends do.
就是一起  消磨时间
You... you spend time.
你太容易被看穿了
You're so transparent.
他的妻子刚刚过世
The man's wife just died.
能不能有点同情心  你个小兔崽子
Have some compassion, you little shit!
对不起  亲爱的  我很抱歉
I'm sorry, honey. I'm sorry.
你妻子刚过世吗
Your wife just died?
是的
Yeah.
怎么死的
How?
她出了车祸  头部受到重创
Massive head trauma, car accident.
能把盐递过来吗
Can you pass the salt?
我之前思考了一下你所说的
I was thinking about what you said about
我对"妈的"这个词使用不当
how I'm not using the f-word properly.
是吗  那你思考后的结果是什么
Yeah? What'd you come up with?
或许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
"妈的"
Fuck
是一个
is a
伟大的词
great word.
"妈的"
Fuck
是一个
is a
伟大的词
great word.
真他妈的棒
Fuck yeah...
天呐  这情况看起来可不妙啊
Oh, man, that don't look good at all.
的确  太糟糕了
No, it don't.
你个傻逼
You dumbass...
我操  真他妈疼
Oh, god damn that fuckin' hurt!
我操  天啊
Shit, yeah!
我们撤吧  赶紧走
Let's go. Get outta here.
亲爱的克里斯
Dear Chris...
真希望我能和你谈谈
I wish I could talk to you.
我怀念我们曾经的生活
I miss how we used to be.
我怀念抱着你  吻着你的小脸
I miss holding you, kissing your face...
我怀念我的小宝贝
I miss my little boy.
你这信是从哪儿寄出的
Where did you send this from?
转角的邮箱里
From the mailbox on the corner.
我以为上一封就是最后一封呢
I thought the last one was the last one.
这样的沙发  我们可以做点什么呢
What do we do with a couch like this?
吻我
Kiss me!
感觉棒极了
Ooh, that feels good!
好的  听我说
Okay, listen to me.
你上一次
When was the last time
十分  特别在意一件事是什么时候
you really, really cared about something?
比如  你小的时候
Like, when you were a kid.
什么东西是你最在意的
What was the most important thing to you?
跑得快
Running fast.
放假时  我们常常在柏油路上赛跑
We used to race on blacktop at recess,
我总是跑得很慢
and then I was always so slow.
我想战胜他们所有人  哪怕就一次
Just once, I wanted to beat 'em all,
把他们都打败
and blow 'em all away.
让他们为我欢呼
Have 'em cheer for me,
而不是为瑞克·罗斯曼或麦克·巴隆欢呼
and not Rick Russoman or Mike Barone,
或是其他跑得快的小杂种
and those speedy motherfuckers.
没错  我想跑得快
Yep. I just wanted to run fast,
远超一切
more than anything.
我是说  甚至超过对霹雳舞的爱
I mean, more than break dancing.
天啊  我能不能有点隐私
Jesus! Can't I get a little privacy?
对不起  对不起  我以为
Whoa! Sorry, man! I thought...
我以为你去上学了
I thought you were back in school!
我今天请假了
I'm taking a personal day.
那是什么
What is that?
没什么
Nothing.
让我看看
Let's see.
是卡尔的
It's Carl's.
你之前开过枪吗
Ever shot a gun before?
到你了
Your turn.
我们开枪打点什么东西吧
Let's shoot something.
比如什么
Like what?
我也不知道  鹿什么的
I dunno. A deer or something.
我觉得这里应该没有鹿
I don't think there are any out here.
松鼠怎么样
What about a squirrel?
等一下
Hold on a second.
你确定那东西没问题吗
You sure that thing's legit?
是的  好吧  确定
Yeah. I mean, yeah.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
你想让我倒数还是怎样
Want me to count down, or like...
我也不知道  你想怎样就怎样
I dunno, do whatever you want.
好吧  我给你来个惊喜
Okay, I'll surprise you.
那就来吧
Surprise me.
保险栓开着
Safety's on.
没错  在左边
Yup, it's on the left side.
对  你要转一下  向...
Yeah, you gotta switch... Turn...
我操
Shit.
感觉怎么样
What'd it feel like?
太他妈爽了
Shit-yeah!
的确很疼  但是
It hurt, but in like a...
痛并快乐着
It's like a good kinda hurt.
那感觉就像
It felt like someone was kinda, um...
操
Shit.
惊喜
Surprise!
你个...你真是个小变态
You are... You are one fucked-up kid.
你也是个变态的成年人
You're one fucked-up adult.
别再这么做了
Don't ever do this again.
操
Fuck!
你太拼了
You're trying too hard.
搞定
And set to go.
谢啦  小哥
Thank you, dude.
打扰下  先生
Excuse me! Sir?
打扰下  先生  你有预约吗
Excuse me! Sir! Do you have an appointment?
没有  马蒂  我只是来逛一圈
No, , I'm just swingin' through!
是米奇尔先生啊  抱歉
Oh, Mr. Mitchell. Sorry.
早啊  兄弟
Hey, buddy.
-戴维斯  -菲尔在吗
- Davis! - Phil here?
在  他们在面试奖学金申请人
Yeah, they're doing the interviews for the scholarship candidates!
头儿  你最好当心了
Mister big! You better watch out!
呼吸  就只有我和水以及...
...breathing. It's just me and the water, and...
抱歉
Sorry.
-大家好  -抱歉
- Hey, guys. - Excuse us.
你好  戴维斯
Hey, Davis.
我们现在没空
We're in the middle of something.
介意我坐这儿吗
Mind if I sit?
嗨  玛格特
Hi, Margot.
你还好吗  兄弟
You okay, pal?
你看上去像是去当建筑工人了什么的
You look like you've been doing construction or something.
斯蒂文  我的脚里扎了根钉子
Steve. I got a fucking nail in my foot.
真他妈疼  不过我现在没事了
It hurt like hell, but I'm okay now.
陶德  你刚刚说到哪儿了
So, Todd, you were saying?
对哦  那个...
Right. Um...
我思路乱掉了
Lost my train of thought.
我们大获全胜
We won.
你们赢下什么了
What'd you win?
游泳比赛  我是个游泳运动员
Swimming. I'm a swimmer.
你游泳吗
Do you swim?
我以前经常去基督教青年会的泳池游泳
You know, I used to do laps at the Y
然后我意识到  一天之内
and then I realized how many people
有多少人在泳池里撒尿
must urinate in that pool on a daily basis,
然后我就再也游不下去了
and that kinda ruined it for me.
我不知道你这是闹的哪出
I don't understand where this is coming from.
你这种轻蔑的姿态  高调的不敬
This contempt, this blatant disrespect!
我感觉有点不对劲  菲尔
Well, something doesn't feel right, Phil.
这整件事  你明白吗
This whole thing, you know?
我想为她做点什么
I wanna do something for her,
但似乎不能...
but this just doesn't...
是你感觉不对
You are not feeling right!
我们必须在今天挑出最终人选
We're picking the finalists today.
我希望你明天签好字  放到我桌上
I want it signed on my desk by tomorrow,
否则你就卷铺盖走人
or you're done here.
我是说  我们之间完了
I mean, we're done.
你为什么要买这些东西
Why you buying all this shit?
都是行业必备工具  小朋友
Uh, the tools of the trade, my young friend.
哪个行业啊
What trade would that be?
破坏  毁灭
Destruction, devastation.
你难道就从来没想过要
I mean, haven't you ever wanted to just
把某个东西砸个稀巴烂吗
smash the shit out of something?
戴维斯  如果我问你一个问题
Davis, if I were to ask you a question,
你一定会老实回答我的  对吧
you'd give me a straight answer, right?
那是你的作风  对一切都很诚实
I mean, that's your thing, being honest about everything.
是啊  的确是我的作风
Yeah, that's my thing.
你觉得我是同性恋吗
Do you think I'm gay?
我不知道  克里斯
I dunno, Chris.
你觉得你是同性恋吗
Do you think you're gay?
我不知道  我觉得可能是吧
I dunno. I think maybe.
我以为你可以告诉我呢
I figured you would tell me.
好吧  那我们一起探讨下
Okay. Let's figure it out together.
你喜欢女孩子吗
Do you like girls?
我不知道
I dunno.
我觉得珍妮弗·海曼很漂亮  她会跟我调情
I think Jennifer Hymen's pretty. She flirts with me.
有时候  我可以透过
And sometimes, I can see the outline
她的上衣看到她的胸罩轮廓  但是...
of her bra through her shirt, but...
我不知道我是真的喜欢她  还是只是喜欢看她
I dunno if I like her, or if I'm just fixating.
珍妮弗·海曼[处女膜]  那是她的真名吗
Jennifer Hymen. That's really her name?
-是啊  -真是糟透了
- Yeah. - That fuckin' blows.
那学校里的男孩们呢
What about the boys at school?
你有喜欢哪个
Is there anybody that you like,
觉得他非常有魅力吗
that you find attractive?
或许是安德鲁·怀特吧
Maybe Andrew White.
他是高三的
He's a junior,
不过我们的体育课是一起上的
and we have the same gym class too.
我们要一起换衣服
We have to get changed together.
你们换衣服时  你会盯着他看吗
Do you watch him when you get changed?
不会
No.
那我觉得你并不是同性恋  克里斯
Well, then I don't think you're gay, Chris.
我是千辛万苦才忍住不看  我必须告诉自己不要看
I have to try not to look. I have to tell myself not to.
好吧  其实  那也很正常
Yeah, no, that's normal, you know.
你年纪这么小  充满着好奇心  那...
I mean you're young, and you're curious, it's...
有时候  我会幻想他的鸡巴插在我嘴里
Sometimes, I imagine his dick in my mouth.
那就不一样了
That's different.
我觉得  你很可能是同性恋
Uh, I would say that you're probably gay.
当然  也可能是双性恋
I mean, you know, or you're bisexual.
但不管是哪种  你都会觉得备受折磨
But I mean, either way, you're gonna get tortured.
我给你的建议就是
I mean, my advice to you, would be
你要在接下来的几年中假装喜欢女孩
to pretend that you like girls for the next few years,
然后搬进城里  明白吗
and then move into the city, you know?
或者去旧金山
Or San Francisco?
如果你喜欢温暖的天气  甚至去洛杉矶也行
Or even Los Angeles, if you like warm weather.
还有其他问题吗
Anything else?
没了
No.
坐进去
Get in.
我们是要干什么来着
What are we doing again?
我们要将我的婚姻全部拆毁
We're taking apart my marriage.
赞爆了
Fuckin' a.
不错啊  继续
Not bad. Keep at it.
保持住  就这样
Now hold it. Just like that.
那是谁
Who's that?
这年头谁他妈还开旅行车啊
Who the fuck still drives a station wagon?
不  我就是想拥有它  我想把它弄回家
No, I just wanna have it... I wanna take it back home,
看把它放在书库或书房里是什么样
see what it looks like in the library or, uh, in the study.
没  完全没看到他
Nope, not a peep out of him.
律师们正在寻求其他解决办法
Lawyers are exploring other options.
我们会让他签字的
We'll get him to sign.
你给他发邀请函了吗
Did you send him an invitation?
拜托  亲爱的
Oh, come on, honey.
是戴维斯去接我放学的
Davis picked me up after school.
他去我家给我帮忙了  干些家务事
Uh, he was helping me around my house. Housework...
谢谢你
Thank you.
一台推土机
A bulldozer.
你几乎可以在易趣网上买到任何东西
You know, you can buy almost anything on ebay.
我只希望它带有操作指南
I just hope it comes with a manual.
别啊  该死
Hey... shit.
有操作指南和保修卡
A manual and a warranty.
她当年好年轻啊
She was so young.
菲尔想立刻跟你谈谈
Phil would like to talk to you immediately.
我一会儿就回来  好吗
I'll be right back, okay?
好的
Okay.
你好啊
Hey there.
你为什么要抽那种垃圾烟  我这儿有好货
Why you smoking that garbage? I got something nice.
我叫陶德  你会游泳吗
I'm Todd. Do you swim?
你竟敢
You dare...
在今晚带了另外一个女人来这里
Bringing another woman here? Tonight?
菲尔  不是你想的那样
Phil, it's not what you think...
你他妈怎么敢这样
How fuckin' dare you?
每一天  我醒来时都会想  为何偏偏带走她
Every day! I wake up thinking, why her?
死去的该是你才对
It should've been you!
已经签了
Signed.
凯伦
So, Karen.
我能摸下你的奶子吗
Can I feel your tits?
茱莉亚的母亲  我  以及她丈夫
Julia's mother and I, and her husband,
想感谢在场的所有人
would like to thank you all
前来陪我们共度这特殊的一晚
for sharing this special evening.
对于那些有幸参与
For those of you who were fortunate enough
茱莉亚的人生的人
to be a part of Julia's life,
你们都知道  她生前是个多好的人
you know what a wonderful person she was.
嗯  没出什么事
Yeah, everything's fine.
美丽的灵魂
A beautiful soul.
留下了太多的记忆
So many memories.
我都不知道该从何谈起
Wouldn't even know where to begin.
但我很确定一件事
But I do know this.
我愿意用全部的记忆
I would trade every one of them
来换取跟我们的女儿再多相处一分钟
for one more minute with our daughter.
茱莉亚可以让人显露出最好的一面
Julia brought out the best in people.
那是她的天赋
That was her gift.
通过茱莉亚·伊斯特伍德-米奇尔奖学金基金会
Now, through the Julia Eastwood-Mitchell scholarship fund,
那一天赋就是她遗留给这世界的东西
that gift will be her legacy.
我想介绍3个年轻人
I'd like to introduce three young adults
在品行和学术方面都十分突出
so outstanding in their character and academic achievements
所以我们没办法只选择一个获得者
that we couldn't choose just one recipient.
有请第一年的奖学金获得者
So please welcome our first-year scholars:
珍妮弗·威廉姆斯
Jennifer Williams.
本杰明·霍华德
Benjamin Howard!
以及仰泳纪录保持者
And the backstroke record-holder himself,
陶德·科勒
Todd Koehler!
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉
Sorry.
她告诉过你们她怀孕了吗
Did she tell you she was pregnant?
就在去年
Last year.
你们知道吗
Did you know?
她为什么没告诉我
Why didn't she tell me?
你想知道为什么吗
You wanna know why?
那不是你的孩子
It wasn't yours.
她跟别人好上了
She was seeing someone.
我带她去做了手术
And I took her for the procedure.
我真希望她留下了那个孩子
I wish she'd kept it.
这是你的退款
Here's your refund.
零钱就不用找了
Keep the change.
戴维斯
Davis.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
他怎么样了
How is he?
他们不肯透露消息  他还在手术室里
They're not saying much. He's, uh, still in surgery.
对方有6个人  把他打得半死
It was six of them beating the shit out of him.
我觉得都是我的错
I feel like it's all my fault.
我他妈就干了一份工作啊
I had one fuckin' job.
莫里诺小姐
Miss Moreno!
宝贝
Baby?
亲爱的
Honey?
听我说
Listen to me.
我再也不会让任何人伤害你了
I won't let anyone hurt you ever again.
我也不会伤害你的
And I won't hurt you either.
我想让你做真实的自己
I just want you to be who you are.
你听见了吗
You hear me?
我会做得更好  我保证
I'll do better, I promise.
等你醒来  你的麻烦大了
And when you wake up, you are in so much trouble.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你叫什么
What's your name?
迈克尔
Michael.
我什么都知道了  迈克尔
I know about everything, Michael.
都没关系
And it's okay.
我只希望  你是真的在乎她
I just hope that you cared for her
因为她应该得到爱
because she deserved that.
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我当时在另一辆车里
I was in the other car.
我...
I was, uh...
就是我的车撞上了你们的车
Driving the car that hit you.
我一直想...
And I've been trying to, um...
我一直...
I've been trying...
-对不起  -没事
- I'm sorry. - It's okay, man.
-真的很对不起  -没事的  老兄
- I'm so sorry. - It's okay, man.
你看不见我
如果天晴
你会想起我
"不是我的椅子  关我屁事"
"Not my chair, not my problem."
你经常这么说吧
Is that what you say?
海马队长先生
你有两分钟的时间
You got two minutes.
谢谢你肯见我  菲尔
Thank you for meeting me, Phil.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我和茱莉亚之间是有过爱的
There was love between me and Julia.
我只是没有好好去经营
I just didn't take care of it.
我觉得奖学金这事...
I think the scholarship is...
很好  我觉得很好
It's good. I think that it's good.
我理解
I understand it.
但我想为她做些别的事
But I wanna do something else for her.
我想着  能不能....
And, uh, I was wondering if, um...
你是否可以参与其中
You'd wanna be a part of it.
我能不能...
Could I...
来  坐下
Go ahead, have a seat.
亲爱的戴维斯  谢谢你的信
Dear Davis, thanks for your letter.
我在缓慢康复过程中
I'm recovering slowly but surely.
除了被人殴打  我必须说
Despite the ass-kicking, I must say,
做真实的自己真是爽爆了
being myself feels good.
顺便说下  我妈离开了卡尔
By the way, mom left Carl, fyi.
十  九  八
Ten! Nine! Eight!
我给你准备了一份小礼物
I have a little gift for you.
七  六  五  四
Seven! Six! Five! Four!
本周六上午11点整请去64号码头
Be at pier 64 this Saturday at 11:00 A.M. Sharp.
三  二  一
Three! Two! One!
相信我
Trust me.
附  玩蛋去吧
P.S. Go fuck yourself.
诚挚的问候  戴维斯·C·米奇尔
Warmest regards, Davis C. Mitchell.